[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Okay, so the issue we're facing here with this crazy 13th order polynomial fit
好的 我们所面对的这个 由13次多项式拟合曲线所引起的问题
is something called overfitting.
叫做过拟合
So in particular, what we've done is we've taken a model and really,
所以具体来说 我们所做的事情 就是采用了一个模型 并且将它不断地
really, really honed in to our actual observations, but
不断地不断地修正 以符合我们对事物的实际观察结果 但是
it doesn't generalize well to thinking about new predictions.
这个模型在作出新的预测的时候泛化能力并不好
And so the issues actually go beyond just making really crazy predictions.
并且这个问题其实已经超出了仅仅是作出疯狂的猜测
And we're gonna discuss this in a lot more detail in the regression course.
我们会在回归分析的课程中进行更加细致和深入的讨论
But I wanna mention that this is a real problem with any machine learning model or
但是我要指出的是这是一个真实存在的问题 这个问题在你所想到的任何机器学习模型或者
statistical model that you might consider.
统计学模型中都是存在的
So in these cases, we wanna fit a model to data, but
在这些情况下 我们想要针对数据去拟合一个模型 但是
we don't want that model to be so specified exactly to the one data set that
我们不希望这个模型太局限在 我们手中已有的这一个数据集
we have that it doesn't generalize well to new observations we might get.
以至于它不能很好地泛化 无法在我们新观察到的数据上做得很好
Okay, so let's go back to this 13th order degree polynomial fit.
好的 让我们回头再来看看这个13次多项式的曲线拟合
And a question is, do we actually believe this?
然后问题就来了 我们真的相信这个预测吗？
Do we believe that this might be a reasonable fit to the data?
我们真的相信这是一个对数据的合理拟合吗？
And I think as I alluded to before, probably not.
我相信鉴于我之前所提到的 这并不是一个我们能够相信的预测
So although it minimizes the residual sum of squares,
所以即使这个模型能够最小化残差平方和
it ends up leading to very bad predictions.
它也会导致一些非常糟糕的预测
Because I'm sitting here and thinking, well, this quadratic fit that we had,
我坐在这里并且思考着 嗯 这是一个二次曲线的拟合模型
even though it didn't minimize my residual sum of squares as much as that 13th
即使它不像那个13次多项式模型那样 最小化了残差平方和
order polynomial, it still, my gut feeling is, somehow this is a better model.
从我本能的直觉出发 这个一个比之于13次多项式更好的模型
Okay, so a question is, what's going on here, and
好的 那么问题来了 接下去我们怎么办
how do we think about choosing the right model order or model complexity?
我们对选择合适的模型阶数或者说模型复杂度的问题 又是怎样考虑的呢？
Well, what we want, is we want good predictions.
我们想要的是准确的预测
Of course, that's what we're aiming for.
毫无疑问那是我们一直以来的目标
But we can't actually observe the future.
但是我们不能真正地观测到未来
Right, so we can't actually observe that prediction that we want to make and
所以我们不能观测到那些我们想要作出的预测的结果
say did we do a good job or not until we actually go ahead and do it.
并且根据那些结果来评判我们是不是做得够好 直到我们真正地根据自己的模型去做出那些预测
So when we're thinking about choosing our model,
所以当我们在思考如何选择模型的时候
somehow we have to work just with the data that we have.
出于一些原因我们只能够运用我们仅有的那些数据
So how can we think about trying to choose a good model in this case?
所以在这样的情况下我们应该如何考虑 去选择一个好的模型呢？
Well, what we can do is we can think about simulating predictions.
我们能够做的是考虑去模拟预测的过程
So we're gonna take our data set that we have,
所以我们会拿出我们所拥有的数据集
and we're gonna remove some of the houses.
并且我们会去掉一部分房屋的数据
So those are the grayed-out houses here.
就是那些在这里变成灰色的屋子
These are gonna be removed temporarily.
它们会暂时地被排除在外
And we're gonna fit our model on the remaining houses.
并且我们会在剩余的房屋数据上去拟合我们的模型
So all of these guys we're gonna use to fit our model using
所有这些房屋就是我们用来去拟合我们的模型的数据
exactly the kind of methods that we talked about before.
运用和我们之前所讨论过的完全一样的方法
And then what we're gonna do is we're gonna predict.
之后我们要做的就是预测
So I'll go through an erase these x's now and put question marks.
所以我现在把这些叉都擦掉并且在房屋上面画上问号
And say from the model that I just learned on the circled houses,
并且推断说 根据我之前刚刚从圈出来的房屋上学习出的模型
what values do I predict for these question marks?
对于这些打上问号的房屋我究竟会给出什么样的预测呢？
And then I can compare to the actual observed values,
之后我就能把这些预测和真实地观测值进行比较了
because these houses are in my data set.
因为这些都是我的数据集里存在的房屋数据
Okay, so I can use this as a proxy for doing the types of
好的 所以我可以用这样的方式作为一种替代方案
real predictions that I wanna do on data that I haven't yet collected.
作为在我还没有收集到的数据上 去做我想要做的真实预测的一种替代方案
Of course, this type of method only is gonna work well if I have enough
当然 这样的方法能够取得好的效果仅仅是在我有足够的
observations to think about fitting on versus testing my predictions on.
观察数据来拟合模型的情况下 相比于那些我用来预测的数据要是足够的
Okay, so let's introduce a little bit of terminology.
好的 让我们引入少量的一些术语
Well, the houses that we use to fit our model, we call that the training set.
这些我们用来去拟合我们的模型的房屋数据 被称作训练集
And the houses that we're using as a proxy for
而那些作为我们真实预测的替代物的房屋
our predictions, those that we're holding out, we call the test set.
那些我们排除出去的房屋数据 我们称之为测试集
Okay, so let's dig a little bit more into how we're gonna do this analysis.
好的 现在让我们来更加深入地讨论一下 我们该如何进行这样的分析
And the first thing that we can do is look at something called the training error.
我们能做的第一件事就是看看所谓的训练损失
So we're gonna examine every house in our test data set.
我们将要检查所有在我们的测试集中出现的房屋
So let's look at this red color here.
现在让我们来看看这些红色的圈
So all of our training houses are represented
这代表了我们训练集中的房屋
with these blue circles here, and these are the only houses
这些房屋用蓝色的圆来表示 并且它们是仅有的
we're gonna look at when we're thinking about defining our training error.
我们在定义和计算训练误差时所着眼的数据
So in particular,
所以具体地来说
we're gonna look at what are the errors that we make on these houses?
我们将要看看我们在这些房屋上有多少的损失
So this is just the residual sum of squares on the houses in our training
所以这仅仅是在我们的训练集上的残差平方和
data set, and that's called the training error.
这称作训练损失
So in particular, the training error looks exactly like what we had for
所以具体地说 训练损失的计算 看上去非常像我们之前所做的
our residual sum of squares calculation, but
关于残差平方和的计算 但是
we're only including the houses that are present in our training data set.
在这里我们仅仅引入了那些在训练集中包含的数据
Okay, so then for any given model, such as a linear fit through the data,
好的 所以对任意给定的模型来说 比如对数据的线性拟合
quadratic fit, or so on, what we can do is we can think about estimating our model
二次拟合或者其他的模型 我们能做的就是估计模型的
parameters as those that minimize the training error.
参数 使得训练损失得到最小化
So that's equivalent to what we talked about before of minimizing the residual
所以这就等价与我们之前讨论的 关于如何最小化
sum of squares.
残差平方和
But again, here we're only looking at the houses in our training data set.
但是我要再次提醒 在这里我们仅仅着眼于在训练集中的房屋数据
Okay, so then that's how we get our estimated w hat,
好的 这就是我们如何得到w hat估计值的方法
our estimated model parameters.
也就是我们模型的参数估计值
But then what we wanna do is we wanna take these estimated model parameters, and
但是之后我们想要做的是 我们想用这些模型参数的估计值
we wanna say how good are we doing?
去推断说我们究竟做的多好
And remember what we said, what we're gonna do,
还记得我们之前所说的吗？ 我们将要做的
is we're gonna look at our held out observations, okay?
是看看模型在我们排除在外的那部分观测数据上 做得怎么样 对吗？
So here, these gray circles are the houses that are in our test set.
在这里 这些灰色的圆 就是在我们的测试集中的房屋数据
So these are houses that were not used to fit this model.
这些是我们没有用来拟合我们模型的数据
And we're gonna say how well are we predicting these actual house sales?
然后我们会问 在这些实际的房屋数据上 我们预测得有多好呢？
Okay, and so what were our predictions?
好的 那么我们的预测值究竟是什么呢？
Well, remember when we thought about making a prediction,
还记得当我们在考虑作出预测的时候
we just used the value of the fit, so just the point on the line.
我们直接使用了拟合曲线上对应的数值 就是这些在曲线上的点
So to assess how well we're predicting these held-out observations,
所以去评价我们在这些排除在外的数据上预测得多好
our test data, we're gonna look at something that, again,
也即在我们的测试集上表现的多好 我们将会再次考虑一些东西
looks exactly like residual sum of squares.
这看上去和剩余方差的和一模一样
But it's called our test error,
但是它被称作测试损失
where we take these estimated model parameters w hat, and we sum
我们用这些模型参数的估计值w hat 然后求和
over our residual sum of squares over all houses that are in our test data set.
对于我们测试集中所有房屋的剩余方差的和 进行求和
Okay, so that's our test error.
好的 这就是我们的测试损失
But what we can think about is we can think about how does test error and
但是我们可以进一步考虑的是 我们的测试损失
training error vary as a function of the model complexity?
和训练损失 是否随着模型的复杂度 呈一个函数变化的关系呢？
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community